<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>coyle.io</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.5</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 23:30:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>3 Goals for 2015</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/y6wh2vx.jpg?1" alt="Filing Cabinet"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the year winds down, it is time to start reflecting on 2014; &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
what went right, what went wrong and what should be changed in 2015?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My list of three goals for 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="1eathealthier"&gt;1. Eat healthier&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;  
  &lt;p&gt;To keep the body in good health is a duty... otherwise we shall not be able to keep our mind strong and clear. 
  - Buddha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't point at 2014 and say that this year, has been particularly devasating to my health. There has been a slow and steady decline, over a period of a few years, in the amount of effort and significance I have put into my physical well being. I want to make a lasting change in the foods I consume. In the past, following a particular diet has not been sustainable. This time around, I will refrain from eating foods that have the largest negative impact on my health. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;  
&lt;li&gt;Red Meats  &lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bovine_somatotropin"&gt;Dairy&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://authoritynutrition.com/9-ways-that-processed-foods-are-killing-people/"&gt;Processed Foods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h5 id="2makemyfamilyapriority"&gt;2. Make my family a priority&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;  
  &lt;p&gt;“Action expresses priorities.” 
  ― Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very intentional with my personal development and I am lucky enough to have a wife that fully supports and believes in me. Unfortunately, I have not been very intentional with the development of my marriage. With all the change 2014 brought, I took for granted how special my wife is to me. So 2015 will be a 180° from 2014 in regards to my family. My wife's &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Five_Love_Languages"&gt;love languages&lt;/a&gt; are acts of service and quality time. So in 2015, I will write her one letter a week, fully plan one special night a week and will take care of dinners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="3journaleverysingleday"&gt;3. Journal every single day&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;  
  &lt;p&gt;“Writing is the only way I have to explain my own life to myself.” 
  ― Pat Conroy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have this goal more from curiosity than any specific outcome. I want to answer the question "What changes will occur from a daily habit of writing my thoughts and actions down".&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/3-goals-for-2015/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">92e1fd9b-087b-4195-8884-3146b8ce2f61</guid><dc:creator>Dennis Coyle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Simplify</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/iNHk5FB.jpg" alt="Potted Plant"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Truth is ever to be found in the simplicity, and not in the multiplicity and confusion of things.”&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;― Isaac Newton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past three months have been a whirlwind for my family. My son Jackson was born nine weeks ago today. With Jackson, came an upheaval of our daily routines, lack of sleep and an abundance of uncertainty surrounding my parenting abilities. As the chaos ensued, I struggled to keep the majority of my pre fatherhood responsibilities and routines in place. I maintained everything, yet I was not quite able to do any single thing well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days ago I read a wonderful &lt;a href="http://www.kylevanpelt.com/build-your-network-risk-game/?utm_content=bufferb85e9&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; from my friend &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/KyleVanPelt"&gt;Kyle Van Pelt&lt;/a&gt;. In the post kyle discusses how to use the same strategies one would use in the game of Risk, towards building out a great personal network. The main strategy being, fortifying your core before trying to expand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most things in life, I read this strategy in the context of my current place in life. I have added on a great deal of responsibility and I have added it onto a very core part; my family. If a core aspect of life is in turmoil, everything else on the periphery will suffer. Conversely, if everything on the periphery is in upheaval yet the core is stable and well reinforced, life will be viable. As simple and intuitive as this is, I had completely missed it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, this is one of those times that I need to strategically retreat, focus on rebuilding the core and simplify the periphery. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/simplify/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">25fdc911-e2ce-4b28-90db-d765b278477e</guid><dc:creator>Dennis Coyle</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 22:28:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Culture of Success</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/FDxtUYa.jpg" alt="Man In Suit"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don't tell people how to do things, tell them what to do and let them surprise you with their results.&lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;-- George S. Patton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common paradigm for success, especially in corporate America, is to work your way up the ladder. On the way up the ladder you out maneuver your fellow ladder climbers, amassing two-faced relationships, and knowledge of how the system works. This knowledge becomes the managers most prized possesion. By keeping  their knowledge secret, they make it more difficult on the next crop of climbers, thereby securing their relative position on the ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By aligning individual's definition of success with that of the company, startups completely change the incentive structure for the organization. Success in the startup is based solely on an individual's results. The expectations are clearly set and the vaugeness of the task removed. How the task is accomplished, whether you come in at 6:00am or 3:00pm to acomplish the task, or decide to accomplish it next to the pool is irrelevent. Results are the only metric that a member of the team is judged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amazing side effect of linking individuals success by their results, knowledge is no longer coveted as a way to keep your job. Information of how to accomplish a task is freely shared because it no longer hurts the knowledge holder to release what they know. By removing the politcal nature of ladder climbing and replacing it with a culture of rewards for results, a company can easily act as a single being, organicaly moving towards the same goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/culture-of-success/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1ae6c513-30b5-46d3-a8df-5a0efc81f4d3</guid><dc:creator>Dennis Coyle</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 22:25:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Iterate</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/2yiKlB1.jpg" alt="Plane"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The way to get started is to quit talking and begin doing.” —Walt Disney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a curse of mine to attempt perfection before I started anything. I would study, research, analyze and find every possible point of failure before I broke ground. Even after starting, at the first sign of difficulty, I would stop and begin the process again. This stop, analyze, start cycle would continue until I got frustrated at the lack of progress and threw in the towel on the whole idea. It took marrying my &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/jesslcoyle"&gt;wife&lt;/a&gt; to kick me in the butt and out of my comfort zone. I didn't want to appear a quitter, so I would just quickly finish what I started, even if the result wasn't the picture of perfection I originally had in mind. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iteration has been a &lt;a href="https://books.google.com/ngrams/graph?content=iterate&amp;amp;year_start=1800&amp;amp;year_end=2000&amp;amp;corpus=15&amp;amp;smoothing=3&amp;amp;share=&amp;amp;direct_url=t1%3B%2Citerate%3B%2Cc0"&gt;popular&lt;/a&gt; word in the tech scene for quite awhile now and alot of great businesses have been built around the concept. Instead of the slow release cycle of a product, (think Windows Operating systems) where there is one release and nothing is updated until the next version. We now see weekly updates to Facebook, our iPhone apps, even our &lt;a href="http://www.automobilemag.com/features/news/1402-tesla-ceo-elon-musk-townhall/"&gt;cars&lt;/a&gt;. The reason behind this is, business leaders are able to see what succeeds in the market and what fails, easily dropping features and improving others, without a huge loss of time, money, or effort. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same concepts of iteration that have made &lt;a href="http://www.thinkwithgoogle.com/articles/8-pillars-of-innovation.html"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2006/11/14/uietips-article-the-freedom-of-fast-iterations-how-netflix-designs-a-winning-web-site/"&gt;Netflix&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/inside-pinterest-an-overnight-success-four-years-in-the-making-2012-4#!JTm4S"&gt;Pinterst&lt;/a&gt; successful, can be applied to achieving personal goals, dieting, budgeting, studying, and just about any other area in your life. By just starting now and actively reflecting on what works and what doesn't, changing accordingly, and starting the process again, you can achieve better results faster than making perfection your goal.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/iterate/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">dbba6c60-788f-4f03-93a8-5e7dcc1b1a12</guid><dc:creator>Dennis Coyle</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 22:23:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Change</title><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/0yG6DSb.jpg" alt="Computer Room"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Only Thing That Is Constant Is Change -”. ― Heraclitus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above quote has never held more truth than it has the preceding three years of my life. I married my best friend, graduated college, moved five times, worked at four different companies and am now expecting a child. The person I am today, would be unrecognizable to the person I was only three years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accepting and welcoming change with open arms was a definite paradigm shift. Yet, through all of the events of the last few years, I would say it is the top skill I have acquired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change is an ever present component of the tech startup community. Noticing something that needs to be changed and changing it, is the very essence of what creates value for startups. Manual processes and tasks that are being done by people, that continue to do them the same way because, "that's the way it's done", are the people corporate America are built by. Assembly line workers, that come to work at 9am, do their specific tasks until 5pm, Monday-Friday, fifty weeks a year, until they retire and get that gold watch for their years of loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Embracing change, asking how can I do this better?, How can I do this more efficiently, and best of all, How can I leverage technology to not do this at all?, is the defining characteristic of the Entrepreneur. In a tech startup, the entire team needs to value change, if they are to survive. Pivoting quickly and changing direction midstream, is what allows the startup to out maneuver the big players. If even one team member doesn't like change and fights changing, it will slow down growth and could cause the startup itself to be out maneuvered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to love change, see change as valuable and leverage change to grow.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/change/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">e263c64a-e4da-467f-a73c-3d534a719269</guid><dc:creator>Dennis Coyle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 22:18:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>